Guide to the Cody Pfanstiehl papers, 1967-1982 MS2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Administrative records, 1967-1982; MS2016 Series 1; 3.25 Linear feet
  - Reports, 1973-1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions and Agreements, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Resolutions and Agreements, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Resolutions and Agreements, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Resolutions and Agreements, 1973-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Financial records, 1967-1982; MS2016 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  Materials in the Financial Records series cover the financial status of WMATA and of its various departments. Budgets, requests for grants and loans, and Congressional allocations are included. Most of the documents are multiple-page memoranda, original and photocopy. The Budgets and Budget Estimates are bound volumes.
  - Financial Matters, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Financial Matters, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Financial Matters, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Financial Matters, 1976-1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Appropriations, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Appropriations, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Appropriations, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Appropriations, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Budget and Budget Estimates, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Application of WMATA for Capital Loan, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Audited and other Financial Statements, 1976 June (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Budget Revision, FY, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Capital Cost Estimate Evaluation, 1975 May (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cost Reduction Program, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Financial Analysis of Jurisdictional Costs, 1978 April-May (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Financial Plan for 100-mile Adopted Regional System, 1977 December (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Metrobus/Metrorail Funding Reviews, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Metro E and F Corridor Transit Alternatives, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Net Income Analysis, 1969 February (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Net Income Analysis, January, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Review of WMATA Program Status, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Policies for Funding Public Transportation, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary WMATA Financial Plan, 1978 January (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Proposed Financial Plan for Metrorail (vol. 1 & 2), 1978 August (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Proposed Financial Plan for Metrorail, 1978 August (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Second Quarter Subsidy Report, FY 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Status of Interim Capital Contributions, 1978 October (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Transit Bonds, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - WMATA Application for Mass Transportation Capital Improvement Grant, 1972 December (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Public relations files, 1967-1982; MS2016 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  The Public Relations series relates to WMATA technology and personnel in the public eye. This series contains in-house newsletters and magazines designed to better inform WMATA employees of events within the Authority. It also contains press releases, transcripts of speeches, transcripts of radio and television broadcasts, and notes demonstrating public awareness of Metro. Most of the series consists of photocopied and original multiple-page memoranda. The in-house and public-information newsletters are matte or glossy bound or newspaper volumes, some oversize.
  Also included are news releases, newsletters and magazines and statements, speeches, and presentations. Such newsletters and magazines include The Tale Light, Inside Metro, Metro Memo and Metro Memo Tabloid, Metro's Sidewalk Superintendent, and Intercom, all published by WMATA for in-house and public reading. Many of the speeches were made on occasions of significance to Metro history, by lights such as Mayor Washington.
  - News Releases, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - News Releases, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - News Releases, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - News Releases, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - News Releases, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - News Releases, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - News Releases, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - News Releases, 1977 January-June (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - News Releases, 1977 July-December (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - News Releases, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - News Releases, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - News Releases, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Inside Metro, 1969 March-December (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Inside Metro, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Inside Metro, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Inside Metro, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Inside Metro, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Inside Metro, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Inside Metro, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Intercom, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Intercom, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Intercom, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Metro Memo, 1977 December (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Metro Memo Tabloid, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Metro's Moving Uptown!, 1981 December (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Metro's Sidewalk Superintendent, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - The Tale Light, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1970 January-May (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1970 June-December (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1971 January (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1971 July-December (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Statements, Speeches, and Presentations, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Subject files, 1967-1982; MS2016 Series 4; 8.5 Linear feet
  The Subject Files series is the largest of the series consisting of arbitrations, biographies, brochures, chronologies, civil action suits, conferences, legislation, maps, metroclips, newspaper clippings;, public hearings reports and statistics. Specific conference include Airlie Transportation Conferences held at Airlie House in Virginia, which was important for developing the basic standards for the Washington Metro.
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1976 November (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1977 April (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1978 November (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1980 March (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1980 May (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Arbitration: WMATA and ATV local 689, 1980 December (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Biographies, 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Biographies of Board Members and Key Staff, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Biographies of Board Members and Key Staff, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - All About Metro, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Brochures, 1971-1980 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Brochures, 1970-1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Brochures on Station Openings, 1977-1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Chronologies, 1970-1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Civil Action Suits, 1972-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Airlie V, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Airlie VI, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Airlie VII, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Airlie VIII, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Airlie IX, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Airlie X, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Airlie XI, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Airlie XII, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Airlie XII, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Airlie XV, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Airlie Financial Plans, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Airlie XVI, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Airlie XVII, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Airlie XVIII, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Legislation Hearings, 1970-1980 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Legislation Relating to the Development of Rapid Transit in DC Area, 1965 September (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Legislation Relating to the Development of Rapid Transit in DC Area, 1972 February (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Legislation Relating to the Development of Rapid Transit in DC Area, 1976 June (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Realtor, 1975 February (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Mass Transit, 1975 March (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Subway, Fall, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Metrorail System Maps, 1962-1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Metrorail System Maps, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Metrorail System Maps, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Metrorail System Maps, 1977-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Metrorail System Maps, 1977-1982 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1972 January-April (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1972 May-December (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1973 January-May (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1973 June-December (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1974 October (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1974 December (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1975 January (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1975 February (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1975 March (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Metroclips, 1975 April (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Metroclips, 1975 May-June (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1975 July-August (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1975 September-November (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1976 March (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1976 April (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1976 May-June (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1976 July (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1976 August (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1976 September (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1976 October (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1976 November (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1976 December (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1977 January (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1977 February (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1977 March (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1977 April (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1977 May-June (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1977 July-August (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1977 September (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1977 October (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1977 November (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1977 December (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1978 January (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1978 February (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1978 March (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Metroclips, 1978 April (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Metroclips, 1978 May (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1978 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1978 July (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1978 August (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1978 September (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1978 October (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1978 November (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1978 December (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1979 January (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1979 February (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1979 March (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1979 April (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1979 May (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1979 June (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1979 July (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1979 August (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1979 September (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1979 September-October (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1979 November (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1979 December (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1980 January (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1980 February (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1980 March (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1980 April (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1980 May (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Metroclips, 1980 June (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Metroclips, 1980 July (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1980 August (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1980 September (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1980 October (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1980 November (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1980 December (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1981 January (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1981 February (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1981 March (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1981 April (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1981 May (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1981 June (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Metroclips, 1981 July (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Metroclips, 1981 August (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Metroclips, 1981 September (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Metroclips, 1981 October (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Metroclips, 1981 November (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Metroclips, 1981 December (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Metroclips, 1982 January (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Metroclips, 1982 February (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Metroclips, 1982 March (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Metroclips, 1982 April (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Metroclips, 1982 May (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Metroclips, 1982 June (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Metroclips, 1982 July (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Metroclips, 1982 August (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Metroclips, 1982 September (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1968 March-December (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1969 June-September (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1969 November-December (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977 January-July (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Record, 1960-1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Notice of General Public Hearings, 1964-1970 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Notice of General Public Hearings, 1971-1974 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #8-15, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #18-24, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #25-26, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #27-30, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #32-38, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #61-1968, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #78-1987, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #92-101, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #102-105, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #113-11./ "Metrorail Alternative Analysis,", 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #117-128, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #132.140-144, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, #145-172, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Notice of Metrobus Public Hearings, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Notice of Metrorail Public Hearings, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Notice of Metrorail Public Hearings, 1980-1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1968 January-April (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1968 May-December (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Reports, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1971 January (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1971 February-May (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1971 July-October (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1971 November (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1971 December (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1972 January-October (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1972 November (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1972 December (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1973 January (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1973 February-May (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1973 May-June (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1973 June-December (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1974 January-February (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1974 July-December (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1975 January-February (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1975 March (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1975 March (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1975 March (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1975 April-December (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1976 January (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1976 January-December (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1977 January (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1977 February (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1977 March (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1977 April (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1977 June-July (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1977 July-August (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1977 September (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1977 September (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1977 October (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1977 November (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1977 December (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1977 December (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1978 January-February (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1978 March (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1978 March (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1978 April (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1978 April (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1978 May-July (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1978 July (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1978 July (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1978 September-October (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1978 November-December (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1979 January (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1979 March-June (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1979 July-December (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1980 January (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1980 March (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Reports, 1980 April-June (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1980 July (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1980 July (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1980 August (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1980 October-December (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1981 January-April (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1981 May-December (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1982 February-June (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1982 July-August (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Construction Schedules, 1967-1980 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Metrorail Timetables, 1971-1981 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Statistics, 1968-1981 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1967-1982; MS2016 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet
  The material in this series include awards, music, photographs and materials related to public interest.
  Pfanstiehl's sense of humor is most apparent as displayed in the music. At a gathering of Metro officials prior to the crucial 1972 funding debate, he sang "Do Not Forsake Me O My Darlin'" from the movie High Noon. Following the successful outcome, when President Nixon succeeded in releasing highway funds for Metro use, he drafted a re-worded version of "Happy Days are Here Again" for another, informal, gathering.
  - Awards, 1971-1981 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Documents, 1970-1977 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Music, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Public Interest, 1972-1977 (Box 32, Folder 8)